Dakota L. Ewigman

■ dakota@ewigman.com | 🗖 816-225-6502 | 🕈 Seattle, WA | **in** linkedin.com/in/DakotaEwigman

Summary _

Software Developer with 10 years of experience in software engineering largely working on frontend web development. Have a broad set of skills and experiences ranging from Full stack Web development, automation tools, testing, and browser development. Highly self-motivated and solution-oriented team player with a growth mindset and passion for technical problem solving.

Experience ____

Software Engineer Redmond, WA

MICROSOFT CORPORATION

Edge Wellet

- Edge Wallet
- Xpay Promo Offers
- Xpay Donation & web apps
- BingAds

Software Engineering Intern

MASTERCARD INCORPORATED

June 2015 – Aug 2015

Automated/versioned setup of development environment

• Evaluated and upgraded UX of existing web-app for customers

Freelance App Developer
TechniPhi
Jan 2015

Developed Android App to exist with existing web-app

• Defined Specs for web APIs

• Self-taught a lot of common practices/skills while on the job

Software Engineering Intern

Kansas City, MO

July 2016 - Present

O'Fallon, MO

May 2013 – Aug 2014

• Developed and ran 20 one week long app development summer camps for K-8th grade children

- Developed and maintained website for information, registration and payment for the camps
- Developed tools to use for learning and collaboration
- · Created an app for tracking and monitoring servers mantenence

Education

CERNER CORPORATION

BS in Computer Science, BS in Computer Engineering

GPA: 3.47/4.00

MISSOURI UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY

Aug 2012 - May 2016

Student Council Webmaster & Student IT Chair, Delta Sigma Phi Webmaster & Treasurer

Skills

Programming JS/Typescript, C#, C++, T-SQL Design HTML, CSS, Markdown, LATEX

Frameworks React, Redux, Knockout, web components

Software Tools Git, Powershell, Bash

Miscellaneous MS Office, Android, Windows, Linux, Azure DevOps, GitHub

Awards

2021

Greatness Award - Customer Obsessed, BingAds Engineering